(非洲)
准备起飞！
OK. Wind her up, boys!
要么蒙特卡洛，要么九泉之下
It's Monte Carlo or bust.
- 起落架  - 搞定
- Struts.  - Check.
- 机翼  - 搞定
- Flaps.  - Check.
- 钻石和黄金  - 搞定
- Diamonds and gold.  - Check.
我们几周后在赌城玩够了就回来
We'll be back from our gambling spree  in a couple weeks.
- 再见  - 或者金子用完的时候我们再回来
- Bye!  - Or whenever the gold runs out.
- 再见啦  - 再见
- Buh-bye!  - Good-bye.
一路走好，等着你们回来！
All right! We'll be waiting for you!
开什么玩笑，我们才不会回来！
Just kidding!  We're never coming back!
什么，你说什么？
Sorry! What was that?
时空加速启动
Initiate warp drive.
他们是说再也不会回来了？
Did they just say  they were never coming back?
人呢？
Guys?
马蒂？
Marty?
太好了，你在这儿！
Oh, goody, you're here!
你要不要尝尝这个？
Why don't you just chew on this?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
我跟你开玩笑呢
I'm just messing with you.
我几年前尾巴就没感觉了
I lost all feeling  in this thing years ago.
梅尔曼？你怎么长成那样了？
Melman? Why do you look like that?
看看谁家孩子在说话呢
Look who's talking.
格洛丽亚？你们怎么看起来都这么…老？
Gloria? Why are you guys so... elderly?
你最近一次照镜子是什么时候？
Now, when was the last time  you looked in the mirror?
什么？
What?
不
No!
醒醒！醒醒！亚力…亚！
Wake up! Wake up, Ally-Al!
- 醒醒！  - 马蒂！
- Wake up!  - Marty!
马蒂，太吓人了
Marty, it was horrible.
又做那个噩梦了？
That same nightmare again, huh?
我们被困在非洲这边了，  都年纪大了，脸上还长满皱纹…
We were stuck here in Africa,  and we were all super-old and wrinkly...
好吧，我也老了，  但是你们看上去都糟透了！
Well, I aged well,  but the rest of you looked terrible!
放松，亚力克斯，  我们为你准备了一个惊喜！
Relax, Alex.  'Cause I got a surprise for you!
是企鹅们回来了吗？  他们准备把我们带回家吗？
Is it the penguins?  Have they come to take us home?
不是，是第二好的事情
Nope. But it's the next best thing.
又是无聊的一天
Another day bites the dust.
来吧
Come on, now!
看好了，小心，小心草皮
Watch it. Watch yourself. Small divots!
抱歉，有点陡，爬上小上坡
Sorry, little incline there.  Back up this hill.
有根低悬的树枝，就在悬崖边，看？
A low-hanging branch,  then just over this bluff and voil?
生日快乐，老兄！
Happy birthday, pal!
哇哦
Whoa.
哇！纽约城
Wow! New York City.
惊喜吧！
Surprise!
格洛丽亚，你是自由女神！
Gloria! You're the Statue of Liberty!
快，给个大拥抱吧！
Bring me your huddled masses, baby!
梅尔曼，你是布鲁克林大桥！
And, Melman,  you're the Brooklyn Bridge!
其实，我是三区大桥
Actually, I'm the Triboro Bridge.
这都是你们做的嘛？
Wow! You guys made this?
是啊，凭记忆做的，  凭着对纽约冲动而迷恋的记忆
Yeah. From memory!  From crazy, obsessive memory.
第五大道…还不堵车！
Hey! Fifth Avenue... with no traffic!
时代广场，摩登时尚却毫无个性
There's Times Square, with its  modern-day corporate lack of character.
一条街上有9家杜恩里德药店！
Nine Duane Reades on the same street!
还有动物园
And the zoo.
我们的家
Wow, our home.
有个迷你版的我！
Look! There's a little me.
还有迷你版的所有人！
And little all of us-es!
亚力克斯！亚力克斯！亚力克斯！
Alex! Alex! Alex!
不！
Oh, no!
你们，你们让我悲喜交加
You guys.  You've both made and ruined my day.
许个愿吧，亲爱的
Make a wish, sweetheart.
你的美梦成真了！
Your wish has come true!
欧耶！
Oh, yay!
我的胃在叫！
My tummy is speaking to me!
噢，真恶心！
Oh, gross!
如果我是你，我不会吃那块蛋糕
I wouldn't eat that side of the cake  if I were you.
亚力克斯，你许了什么愿？
Alex, what was your wish?
我希望我们都能回家  不要误解
I wished we could go home.  I mean, don't get me wrong.
我爱这个礼物，但它不是真的
I love this.  But it's not the real thing.
因为它是泥塑的模型，亚力克斯
That's because it's a mud model, Alex.
这不是真的纽约，这点很清楚
It's not actually New York.  I hope that was clear.
我们在干嘛？
What are we doing?
指望企鹅回来带走我们吗
Here we are relying on the penguins  to come back for us.
但是…我们应该直接去蒙特卡洛找到他们
But... we should just go to Monte Carlo  and get them.
我们一个狮子，一个斑马，  一个长颈鹿，一个河马
How do a lion, a zebra,  a giraffe and a hippo walk
怎么能进蒙特卡洛的赌场？
into a casino in Monte Carlo?
我怎么知道，问牧师吧！
I don't know. Ask the rabbi!
- 我是认真的  - 来吧
- Hey, I'm serious.  - Come on!
我们能做到！  我们什么都做得到！团结就是力量！
We can do it!  We can do anything! It's us!
团结就是力量！
We're us!
就是这样，我们都快环游过世界了！
Yeah, that's right.  We've gone halfway around the world!
相比之下，蒙特卡洛真是近在咫尺！
Compared with that, Monte Carlo's  just a hop, skip and a swim away!
是啊
Yeah.
为了回家
To home.
- 为了回家！  - 为了回家！
- Home!  - Home.
- 为了回家  - 为了汉堡
- Home.  - Cheeseburger.
你猜怎么着，企鹅们见到我们肯定会很开心的
Tell you what, bet those penguins  will be glad to see us.
是啊，他们肯定无聊死了！
Yeah, they're probably  bored out of their minds!
跟我玩枕头大战，你们都太娘们儿啦！
You pillow fight  like a bunch of little girls!
靠，这些枕头都是用小鸟羽毛做的！
Chimichanga! These pillows  are filled with baby birds!
《马达加斯加3：欧洲通缉犯》
(蒙特卡洛港口)
怎么了？
What?
就在这里，赌场！
There it is. The casino!
什么？
What?
我说，太好了  我们能在这里找到企鹅
I said, "Perfect.  That's where we'll find the penguins."
什么？
What?
来吧
Come on, guys.
企鹅们天生不会低调
Operation Penguin Extraction  does not include levity.
我们不能让自己引起注意
We can't draw attention to ourselves.
我们是隐身的！
We're invisible!
我讲话很轻很轻
I'm talking really, really quiet.
大家快来一起跳！
Everybody dance now!
耶！耶！耶！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
大家快来一起跳！
Everybody dance now!
耶！
Yeah!
第一步，闯进赌场，逮住企鹅
OK. Phase One: We break  into the casino, grab the penguins,
让他们用猴子驱动的超级飞机
and get them  to take us back to New York
带我们回纽约！
in the Monkey-Powered Super Plane!
好
Check.
第二步，我们严厉谴责，  企鹅在非洲抛弃我们
Phase Two: We chew out the penguins  for abandoning us in Africa.
好
Check.
第三步，我们跟企鹅道歉
Phase Three:  We apologize to the penguins
说对他们谴责太过严厉，  但是要点到为止
for overly harsh chewing outing,  but we've gotten our point across.
第四步，回到纽约城
Phase Four: Back to New York City.
- 太好了！  - 这计划我喜欢!
- Yes!  - I like it!
好了，我们沿着这些通风管道
All right, we take  these ventilation ducts
爬进赌场的通风管，找到企鹅
to the crawlspace above the casino  where we find the penguins.
只是，每个人该对应哪个管道呢？
I just need to figure out  which duct each of us should take.
∮ 贝斯低音回响 ∮
∮ Pause back with the bass ∮
∮ 即兴表演上场  抓住美好时光 ∮
∮ The jam is live in effect and I don't waste time ∮
∮ 麦克风在手  演绎淋漓酣畅 ∮
∮ On the mic with a dope rhyme ∮
∮ 跟着节奏跳吧 ∮
∮ Jump to the rhythm ∮
∮ 跳吧  跟着节奏跳吧  跳吧 ∮
∮ Jump, jump to the rhythm, jump... ∮
不要
Oh, no!
掩护
Take cover!
- 嗨，亲爱的  - 好吧
- Hi, honey.  - OK!
好好，我来抓着你  我来抓着你，亲爱的
OK, OK. I got you. I got you, honey.
他们不会让动物踏上赌场的
Now, they're not gonna let  animals on to the casino floor,
企鹅一定是做了伪装
so expect some kind of disguise.
看！那个很丑的女人！
Look at that!  That is one ugly, mug-ugly lady!
丑到人神共愤啊！
That is roach-killing ugly!
那不是女人，是凡尔赛之王
That's not a lady.  That's the King of Versailles.
也不是凡尔赛之王
And that's not the King of Versailles.
是猩猩，猩猩就像是烟
That's the chimps.  And the chimps are like smoke.
哪里有烟，哪里就有火  这里的火，就是企鹅！
And where there's smoke, there's fire.  And by fire, I mean the penguins!
凡尔赛之王又赢了
King of Versailles wins again.
听我的没错吧
I say we let it ride.
我们要重拾嬉皮士那一套，荣归纽约
Then we'll pick up the hippies  and fly back to New York in style.
我们能买一架空客A380吗
Can we buy an Airbus A-380?
买架纯金的！
Solid gold, baby!
长官！纯金的飞机是飞不起来的
Sir! A solid gold plane  wouldn't be able to fly.
科瓦斯基，我们是有钱人！  有钱人才不受物理学的限制
Kowalski, we'll be rich!  The rules of physics don't apply to us.
再来！
Let it ride!
没错！
Right-o!
好的，2分17秒后狐猴将切断电源
OK. In exactly two minutes and 17  seconds, the lemurs will cut the power.
- 现在？  - 等等
- Now?  - No.
- 现在行了么？  - 再等等
- OK?  - No.
- 现在呢？  - 不行
- Now?  - No.
我吊下去，抓住企鹅，  你把我拉上来，我们就撤
I drop down, grab the penguins.  You crank me up, and we are out of here.
让我吊下去！我来抓企鹅！
Let me drop down!  I'll grab the penguins!
你没有手指，马蒂
You don't have fingers, Marty.
- 现在，切断  - 不，等等
- Now? Do it?  - No. No!
这是领导者想的事情
These are things a leader  has to think of.
为什么你来当领导者？为什么不是我？
Why should you be the leader?  Why not me?
因为我掌握着计划！
'Cause I'm the phase tracker!
凡尔赛之王现在还在玩呢
The king is letting it ride.
- 我怎么就不知道？  - 你是计划的一部分
- How did I get phased out?  - You're part of a phase.
计划不是纸上谈兵的，你要去做
A phase isn't something you own,  it's something you're in.
就这样
That's it.
谁选你当大计划领导的？
Who voted you  Grand Phase Master anyway?
我，我自己，因为我就是领导者！
Me! I voted me!  'Cause I'm the leader!
- 黑色！  - 没错，宝贝！
- Black!  - That's it, baby!
- 现在可以了吧？  - 不行！
- Now?  - No!
凡尔赛之王全胜！
The King of Versailles wins it all!
- 也许我应该来管  - 梅尔曼！
- Maybe I should be in charge.  - Melman!
我是医生
I am a doctor.
- 就是现在！  - 不行
- Now!  - No.
为什么我们不能都成为领导者？
Why can't we all be leaders?
够了！我来领导
Enough! I'm gonna lead.
近来如何，小猫咪？
What's new, pussycat?
哇哦！哇哦！哇哦！
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
马蒂，我们这是第几步了？
Marty, what phase are we at?
第三步，道歉！
Phase Three: Apologize!
对，老兄，我们实在抱歉
Right. Oh, man, we are so sorry.
没关系，我们滚！
Apology accepted. Let's roll!
马蒂，我们跳过了第二步！  我们都没有谴责他们！
Marty! We skipped Phase Two!  We didn't chew them out!
不关我的事，我听领导的！
Don't look at me.  I'm just following the leader!
- 现在  - 我现在忙着呢
- Now!  - I'm a bit busy right now.
快把开关拉下来
Just pull the switch!
好吧
OK, fine.
见鬼，灯怎么了？
What the heck is going on  with the lights?
∮ 俺告诉你俺想要啥  俺真的想要啥 ∮
∮ Yo, tell me what you want.  What you really, really want ∮
∮ I'll tell you what I want.  What I really, really want... ∮
你们在磨蹭什么？！
What are you doing?!
走人！
Come on!
启动一级戒备！
Initiate lockdown!
把动物管制中心的杜波依队长找来！
And get me Captain Dubois  from Animal Control!
请讲
Speak.
是
Oui.
斑马？
A zebra?
河马？
A hippo?
长颈鹿？
A giraffe?
还有狮子？！
A lion?!
我七岁的时候，掐死了我第一个鹦鹉
When I was seven,  I strangled my first parrot,
溺死第一条金鱼，打死第一条蛇
flushed my first goldfish,  punched my first snake.
现在我终于迎来了一个崭新的时刻，  我的一生都在为这一刻准备着
Now I have finally reached the moment  I have been preparing for my entire life.
我职业的巅峰：
The pinnacle of my career:
捕猎百兽之王！
To hunt the king of the beasts!
- 不是吧  - 紧闭了，是么？
- Oh, no.  - Lockdown, eh?
我们怎么办？
What do we do?
好吧，各位，往后站，  放着我来
All right, everybody, stand back.  I got this one.
当我没说
Never mind.
没错，第一印象的机会只有一次
Well, you only get one chance  at a first impression.
- 刚刚怎么了？  - 我们在哪儿，这是什么？
- What just happened?  - Where are we? What is this?
我们叫它，  豪华突袭游乐车
We call it  the Luxury Assault Recreational Vehicle.
这引擎真爽！
The car goes vroom-vroom!
坐好了
Step on it, boys!
(动物控制中心)
杜波依队长，见到你太好了，  你绝对想不到…
Captain Dubois, I am so happy  to see you! You will not believe...
滚回去，白痴！  你那破古龙水盖住动物体香了！
Get back, you fool! Your cheap cologne  is obscuring the animal musk!
脸好痛！
Oh, my face!
可怜的小动物
Poor, poor animals.
你们不该离开森林的，现在你们是我的了
You should never have left the forest.  Now you deal with me.
科瓦斯基，放信号，让猩猩们开超级飞机
Kowalski, signal the chimps to meet us
到老地方来接我们
at the rendezvous point  with the Super Plane.
国宾大酒店，前进！
Hotel Ambassador. Let's move it!
瞧？长颈鹿在12点方向
Voil? Giraffe at twelve o'clock.
兄弟们，我们被盯上了
Guys, we've got a tail.
狗仔队！
Paparazzi!
油门踩到底，二等兵
Pedal to the metal, Private.
禁止拍照哦！
Don't take any photos, please!
嗨！
Hi!
我在这儿！
Here I am!
不要…拍…照
Don't take... any... photos.
- 不要再拍了！  - 军医！
- No more pictures!  - Medic!
- 预计抵达时间？  - 2分37秒，长官
- ETA to rendezvous point?  - Two minutes, 37 seconds, sir.
准备开战！
Man your battle stations!
等等！没人握方向盘！
Hey! Wait! Nobody's at the wheel!
回去！司机空缺！没有司机！
Get back there! Negative on the driver!  There's no driver!
救命！无人驾驶！  不要！会出车祸的！
Help! Nobody's driving!  Oh, no! We're going to die!
不要光坐那儿，绣花枕头，  抓住方向盘！
Don't just sit there, fancy pants.  Grab the wheel!
开什么玩笑？  我才不开车，我是纽约人！
Are you kidding?  I don't drive. I'm a New Yorker!
挪开，狮子妹妹！
Move over, Miss Daisy!
你在干嘛？斑马才不能开车！  只有企鹅和人会开车
What are you doing? Zebras can't drive!  Only penguins and people can drive.
这些按钮是用来干嘛的？
What do all these buttons do?
救命！
Help me!
干得好，条纹哥！
Nice one, Stripes!
疯女人靠近了！
Crazy woman gaining!
欧米茄3号滑动障碍会搞定的
Our Omega-3 slick will take them down.
二等兵，出手！
Private, activate!
她还不错嘛！
She's good!
科瓦斯基，人肉她
Kowalski, intel.
长官，问题很严重
Sir. We have a serious problem.
香塔尔·杜波依队长
Captain Chantal Dubois.
摩纳哥动物控制中心，  完美记录持有者
Monaco Animal Control.  Perfect case record.
你开错路了，马蒂！
You're going the wrong way, Marty!
快叫我马蒂奥·安德烈蒂  <i>注：马里奥·安德烈蒂，著名赛车手</i>
Just call me Marty-o Andretti.
才不是，你是傻逼奥·安德烈蒂！
No. You're Sucky-o Andretti!
不要指手画脚了！
Stop backseat driving!
我是在帮你，快把方向盘给我
I'm passenger-seat driving.  Give me the wheel.
这才不是方向盘，是我的命根子！
It's not a wheel, it's my baby!
你们的蹄子不是用来抓方向盘的！
Your hoofs aren't meant to be  on a wheel!
- 现在想开车，来不及了！  - 别看着我！
- Hey! Too late for you to drive!  - Don't look at me!
吵架的时候别看我！看路！
Don't look at me when we argue!  Look at the road!
冷静冷静！
Be cool, be cool!
嗨，长官，有问题吗？
Hi, Officer. Is there a problem?
嗨
Hi.
小心！
Watch out!
马力要再大点
We need more power.
轮到科瓦斯基的核反应堆上场了
Time to fire up  Kowalski's nucular reactor.
- 这是核反应堆？  - 没错
- That's a nuclear reactor?  - Nucular.
她在车顶上！
She's on the roof!
但长官，还没准备好
But, sir, it's not ready.
控制棒还要校准
The control rods  will have to be calibrated.
更别说缺少铀238了
And don't even ask me  about the Uranium-238 blanket.
好吧
OK.
马蒂，我们甩掉她了！  你现在可以慢下来了
OK, Marty, we lost her!  Maybe you can slow down now.
慢不下来！没有刹车！
I can't! There's no brakes!
没有刹车？  这是要军法从事的啊，新兵蛋子
No brakes?  Way to commit, soldier.
我们跳车吧
Let's get out of here!
快快快，现在就跳
Go, go, go! Move! Now!
你们都去哪儿呀？
Hey, where's everybody going?
我在飞！
I'm flying!
我在飞耶！我是第一个能飞的猴子！
I'm flying!  I'm the first flying monkey!
耶！
Oh, yay!
我们有办法离开这儿了！
That's our ticket out of here!
太好了！
Yeah, baby!
大家快上猴梯！
Everybody!  On the monkey chain!
香蕉弹上膛！
Deploy banana gun!
抓住这些小家伙，把它们扔上去！  快跑，快跑！
Grab the little guys! Toss them up!  Let's go! Go, go, go! Go!
快！快！赶紧跑！
Faster! Faster! Faster! Come on!
快上了，梅尔曼！
Come on, Melman!
成功了！
Yeah!
梅尔曼！
Melman!
我的脖子！
My neck!
坐回去！发双倍香蕉！
Put your backs into it!  Double banana overtime!
S形飞行！S形飞行！
Serpentine! Serpentine!
这女人真的开始吓到我了
Hey, this lady's  really starting to freak me out.
搞定她，莫特
Fix it, Mort.
抓着
Hold this.
亚力克斯，小心点！她是疯女人！
Alex, be careful! She's crazy!
就你知道么，马蒂？！
You think, Marty?!
搞定！回家！
That's right! Home free, baby!
我能呼吸了！
I can breathe!
拜拜，杜波依！
Au revoir, Dubois!
算你狠，狮子
Well played, lion.
好戏才刚刚开始
Game on.
∮ 纽约，纽约，了不起的城市 ∮
∮ New York, New York  It's a heck of a town ∮
- ∮ 布朗克斯在上 ∮  - ∮ 但炮台公园在下 ∮
-  ∮ The Bronx is up ∮  - ∮ But the Battery's down ∮
∮ 纽约，纽约 ∮
∮ New York, New York ∮
科瓦斯基，汇报状态
Kowalski, status report.
好消息是，这首歌快结束了
So the good news is  this song is almost over.
太好了，坏消息呢？
Well, that's music to my ears.  And the bad news?
齿轮传动装置严重损毁，长官
The gear assembly is  badly damaged, sir.
只是时间问题…
It's only a matter of time before...
我们就不能正常着陆一次么？
Why can't we ever  just make a normal landing?
老天！
Oh, man!
梅尔曼，坚持住好么？  我会把你弄下来的，亲爱的
Hold on, Melman. OK?  I'll get you down, sweetie.
他在哪儿？  要找到朱利安国王，朱利安国王！
Where is he?  Must find King Julien. King Julien!
∮ 天越来越热 ∮
∮ It's getting hot in here ∮
∮ 不如脱掉你的皮 ∮
∮ So take off all your fur ∮
∮ 我越来越热 ∮
∮ I am getting so hot ∮
∮ 我想脱掉我的皮 ∮
∮ I want to take my fur off ∮
老大，飞机状况如何？
Skipper, what about the plane?
猩猩们会连夜修理的，  不分昼夜，舍身忘己
The chimps will work through the night.  No breaks, no safety restrictions.
嘿，你们去哪儿？
Hey, where are you going?
回来！我们签了合同的！
Get back here! We have a contract!
不过，  恐怕法国的劳动法稍许宽松那么一点
Yes. Well, I'm afraid labor laws  are slightly more lenient in France.
他们一年只要工作两个礼拜
You see, they only have to work  two weeks a year.
好吧，总有人有白求恩的职业操守吧！
Well, someone else  has the Canadian work ethic!
你们企鹅，还是可以修好的是吗？是吗？
But you penguins,  you can still fix it, right? Right?
是啊是啊，你们是一只无敌小分队啊
Yeah, yeah. You're  a little crackerjack, can-do team.
你们希望我说实话吗？
You want me to give it to you straight?
好！好！不要
Yes! Yes! No.
可以稍微婉转一点？
Bend it a little?
这架飞机彻底不行了，  坏了，报废了，完结了！
Well, the plane's totaled.  Kaput, blammo, busted!
再也飞不起来了
Never to fly again.
就这样？我们再也回不了家了？
So that's it? That's it then,  we're never gonna get home?
不行！我们一定得回家！
No! We've got to get home!
我们可以修好！我们能修好！  来吧！伙计们！我们能修好它！
We can fix it! We'll fix it!  Yeah, guys, come on, we'll fix it!
先把外面的弄好，然后修里面的
You just start from the outside pieces,  and you work your way in.
就像这样！
And, yeah, perfect!
来呀，不要光站着看！  马蒂，把那边那玩意儿拖过来
Come on! Don't just stand there, guys.  Marty! Drag that thingy over here.
我们只要把这坨接在一块儿，  然后…
And we'll just attach it  to this dealy-bob over here. And...
我们回不去了
We're not going home.
我们永远都回不去了
We're never going home.
是警车！
It's the fuzz!
怎么办？  我们躲得了一时躲不了一世啊！
What are we gonna do?  We can't hide forever!
而且我们还不能藏起来！这又不是非洲
And we can't just blend!  You know this ain't Africa.
那又怎样？
Oh, what's the point?
想想有没有办法
Tell me one conceivable way  that extra-large animals like us
能让我们这种大型动物穿越欧洲
are gonna be able  to move through Europe
还不引起注意
without attracting unwanted attention.
(马戏团  萨拉戈萨)
看…
Hey...
你们哪儿冒出来的？
Where are you coming from?
求求你，让我们避一避风头吧
Please, you got to hide us.  Just until the heat dies down.
外来人员不让进
Absolut no outsiders.
把眼泪鼻涕擦擦干净，滚吧！
So wipe that Smirnoff your face  and Popov!
帮个忙吧，我们都是猫科
Come on, man. You gotta do  one cat a solid. Cat to cat.
哥们儿，帮个忙嘛，求您了
Do a solid here, buddy. Come on.
不行！这列火车只载马戏团动物
Nyet! This train is  for circus animals only.
听上去他们好像遇上麻烦了
They sound like they be in trouble.
斯蒂芬诺，我们不引狮入室，  我不信任狮子
Stefano, we do not invite trouble  into our circus. I don't trust lion.
油头粉面的！
Hair too big and glossy!
维塔利，别这么小气
Aw, come on, Vitaly, you're being mean.
他不是公狮，  是母狮…还带着一窝崽
He not lion.  He lioness... with a beehive.
太尴尬了，我们都听见他们说话了
This is awkward.  We can hear everything they're saying.
这不是我们的错！
It is not our problem!
不不！等等，等等！
No, no! Wait, wait, wait!
再等一下，  他在打电话而且…我们不能赶他走
Just give us a minute. He's on the phone  and... can't get him off!
我们不能把他们扔那儿！
We cannot leave them there!
只有马戏团动物才能上火车！
Only circus animals on this train!
等等，听着！  我们是马戏团的，让我们上来吧！
Wait, listen! We are circus animals.  You got to let us in!
你们真的是马戏团的？
You are really circus?
是，百分百马戏团的！
Yes. Full circus!
我妈妈是马戏团的，  我爸爸也是马戏团的
My momma was circus.  My daddy was circus.
吉亚，把门关上！
Gia! Shut the door!
求你了
Please.
发现了，在那边！
Over there! Over there!
他们是马戏团的，马戏团要团结在一起
They are circus. Circus stick together.
哇，美帝的马戏团！
Wow! Circus americano!
你们一定很出名！
You must all be very famous!
- 是，我们…  - 当然啦
- Yeah, we...  - Absolutely.
我们相当有名…
We're relatively well known...
不过亚力克斯是真的大明星
But Alex is really the star.
我不是…“大明星”  充其量也是…好吧，明星
Well, I'm not... I wouldn't say "star."  More like... well, star.
亚力斯，你的绝招是什么？
What is your act, Alice?
嗯…我基本上…嗯，我跳上石头…
Well... I basically,  uh, I jump up on my rock...
- 石头？  - 对，是一块很高的…石头
- Rock?  - Yeah. It's a very high... rock.
- 超级高！  - 然后呢？
- A really high rock!  - And then?
然后，我会叫一声，  雄赳赳气昂昂地叫一声“嗷！”
And then, well, I roar like...  Iike a serious "Rawrrr!"
- 然后呢？  - 然后我跳下来
- And then?  - And then I jump off the rock.
- 再然后？  - 再…然后？
- And then?!  - And then... And then what?
- 这就完了？  - 跳进水池！
- That is all?  - lnto a pool!
- 满满的一池子水！  - 满满的一池子眼镜蛇！
- Full of water!  - Full of cobras!
其实，好像我是跳进…
Actually, it appears  like I'm jumping in to a pool...
- 眼镜蛇！  - 眼镜水蛇
- With cobras!  - Aquatic cobras.
为了演出效果起见  紧要时刻我会腾空而起
For effect. But I actually pull up  at the last second.
- 腾空而起？  - 对
- Pull up?  - Yeah.
- 怎么做到的？！  - 用威亚！
- How do you do that?!  - Wire harness!
- 用气球！  - 用喷气背包！
- Balloons!  - Jet pack!
我被威亚吊着，点燃喷气背包
I flip off the wire harness,  ignite my jet pack,
再把气球扔给全世界的孩子
and then toss balloons  to the children of the world.
小孩子喜欢，小孩子最喜欢这个了
Kids love it. Kids always love that.
是不是像空中飞人那样？
Is this like the trapeze?
对，飞人！就是这样！
Yes! Trapeze! Exactly!
哇哦！美式空中飞人！
Wow! Trapeze americano!
我有个好主意，  你们跟我们一起去罗马吧！
Hey, I have a great idea!  Maybe you come with us to Roma!
维塔利只是闹着玩，  他很厉害是不是？
Hey, Vitaly is just playing around.  He is good, no?
额，谢谢，不用了
Yeah, thanks. Thanks.
我们下一站就下车
But we're gonna get off  at the next stop
我们要回美国
so we can get back to America.
太巧了！
That is such a coincidence!
因为我们要…我们…
Because we're going... going to...
让我说完！
Let me finish!
我们也要去美国！
We're going to America, as well!
- 什么？！  - 美国？
- What?!  - America?
- 去美国？  - 什么？
- Going to America?  - What?
- 对  - 太好了？什么时候？
- Si.  - Wow? When?
去完罗马，我们去伦敦
After Roma, we go to London.
然后有个大赞助商，  会把我们送到纽约
And then a big-time promoter will see us  and then send us to New York.
他们要去纽约耶！
They're going to New York!
但前提是他要满意
Well, only if he likes what he sees.
纽约？真的吗？  那是我们的家，是我们住的地方
New York? Seriously?  That's our home. That's where we live.
那不是很好？
Isn't that fun?
- 我们能一起去吗？  - 当然！
- Could we go with you?  - Sure!
你们可以和维塔利挤一张床！
You can bunk with Vitaly!
- 哇！  - 不用了吧
- Whoa!  - Or not.
不行！
Nyet!
哦不
Oh, no.
我觉得维塔利不喜欢这个安排，  他要怎样？
I don't think Vitaly likes that idea.  What's he gonna do?
你们谁是领头的？
Which one of you is leader?
告诉你的人，我们这儿有条铁律！
Tell your comrades  there is one rule we do not break!
是说出来，不是喷出来？
Thou shalt say it and not spray it?
不是！
Nyet!
马戏团主人不接纳偷渡者！
Circus owner no allow stowaways!
听见了，俄国佬
I hear you, Russki.
尽管如此，  马戏团老板如果也是偷渡者
Although, the circus owner  may allow stowaways
他还是会允许的哦
if the stowaways  just happen to be the owners.
猜猜看
Riddle me that.
这只衣着光鲜的小鸟在说什么？
What is sharply dressed  little birdie talking about?
给他们瞧瞧
Show 'em, boys.
成交，我的朋友
You have a deal, mi amigo.
我保证这个马戏团会让你大获成功的！
I am sure this circus  will bring you great success!
后会有期，祝你好运！
I guess this is good-bye and good luck!
你们知道怎么运营一个马戏团吗？
What do we know  about owning a circus?
不知道，  不过这是我们回家的唯一机会
Nothing. But it's our only shot  at getting home.
你们最好知道自己在做什么
You better know what you're doing.
你们可是拿着二等兵的大学基金在冒险啊
You're risking  Private's community college fund.
我永远都当不了校长了
I'll never be president.
嘿，这才不是头等舱
Hey, this is not first class.
绝对是普通舱
Definitely coach.
莫特，住手！
Mort! Stop it!
嘿，美女
Hey, gorgeous.
有人说过你像超级模特吗？
Has anyone ever told you  that you look like a supermodel?
虽然有点胖，毛发有点多，体味有点重
Albeit a fat, hairy one who smells.
你有一个柔软的背
You have a very hairy back.
我就喜欢这样的女人
I like that in a woman.
就是这儿，我要进去了
That's it! I'm going in.
不要！太危险了！
Stop! It's too dangerous!
不要逞英雄！
Don't be a hero!
狮子
Lion.
12个小时了
Twelve hours old.
250公斤
Two hundred and fifty kilograms.
光滑的鬃毛，好多护发素
Glossy mane.  Too much conditioner.
一群白痴！
Stupid bozos!
你好，小猫咪！
Hello, kitty!
原来，你是跟马戏团跑了
So, you ran away with the circus.
真没创意
What a clich?
(罗马  700公里)
(罗马  0公里)
什么破地方！
What a dump!
如果想要吸引像样的体育队伍，
If they want to attract  a decent sports team,
应该铲平这老鼠坑，  盖一个新的
they should bulldoze this rat trap  and invest in a new arena.
古罗马斗兽场，马蒂！  环形剧场的鼻祖诶
The Colosseum, Marty!  The original theater-in-the-round.
- 我的祖先曾经在这里表演  - 真的假的！
- My ancestors used to perform here.  - No kidding!
真的，每场演出都有俘虏
Yeah. Every show had  a captive audience.
- 最后都被狮子吃掉了  - 听上去很不错啊
- Apparently, they killed.  - Sounds like a great gig!
还有30分钟！各位！  还有30分钟！
Trenta minuti, everybody!  Trenta minuti!
太让人激动了！
This is so exciting!
记住，我们要低调
Remember, we just lay low.
离演员远点，不要打扰他们
Stay out of the way.  Let them do their thing.
快来看看这个？
Would you look at this?
你们应该回娘胎
You gotta go back  in your momma's belly,
你们太可爱了，都不像三次元世界的人物
'cause you're too cute  to be out here in the real world.
- 嘿，滚开，死驴！  - 哇，怎么回…？
- Oi! Naff off, you muppet!  - Whoa! What the...?
马蒂，他们是专业人士，我们走
Marty, they're professionals. Come on.
你看上去好漂亮！
You look gorgeous!
好了，动物们！  我们是你们的新东家
All right, animals!  We may be your new owners,
但我们不想改变现有的马戏团规矩
but we don't want to reinvent  the circus wheel here,
所以，上台就按老规矩做！
so just go out, do what you do!
就当作是为伦敦的赞助商做热身
Just think of this as a fun warm-up  for that promoter in London.
是吧，马蒂，马蒂？
Right, Marty? Marty?
我想做一匹马戏团的马！
I want to be a circus horse!
我们可以把你漆成白色的！
We could paint you white!
然后把你漆成粉色的！
And then paint you pink!
- 碉堡了！  - 一点都不低调，是吧，马蒂？
- Awesome!  - Not laying very low, are we, Marty?
索尼娅！熊在哪里？  索尼娅！我们要上台了！
Sonya! Where is the bear?  Sonya! We're about to start!
维塔利！
Hey, Vitaly!
笑一个
Got your game face on.
笑得好
Good game face.
这只猫有病吧？
What is that cat's problem?
“我是个俄罗斯贱猫，看谁都不顺眼”
"I'm a mean Russian cat  who isn't nice to anybody."
亲爱的，看！我做到了！
Hey, honey, look! Look, I'm doing it!
不要再玩了
Guys, stop fooling around.
我们只是找点乐子啦
We're just having a little fun.
让那些动物好好演出就好了
Let's let these animals do their show.
嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒，马戏团！  嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒，爆炸头！
Da-da da-da-da-da-da-da, circus!  Da-da da-da-da-da-da-da, Afro!
马戏团 爆炸头  马戏团 爆炸头
Circus Afro  Circus Afro
花衬衫 花衬衫 花衬衫 爆炸头！
Polka dot, polka dot, polka dot, Afro!
要不要这样？
Really?
索尼娅！索尼娅熊你在哪里？！
Sonya! Where is Sonya the bear?!
(梵蒂冈)
我要吻遍你脸上每一个角落
I want to kiss  every inch of your huge head.
可能要花上几周
It may take me a number of weeks.
小心！
Hey, watch it!
有点重
That was heavy.
不要哭，别哭！
Don't cry. Stop crying!
看见你哭我也想哭了，亲爱的
It makes me cry  to see you cry, my darling.
我给你找辆更好的
I will get you something even better.
(杜卡迪摩托车)
金钱是买的到真爱的
Hey, you can buy love.
哇，别开太快！
Whoa, not too fast!
女士们先生们，
Ladies and gentlemen,
由吉亚为大家演出
presenting Gia,
空中飞虎！
the trapeze-flying jaguar!
她来了，向前翻腾三周半，
And there she go.  The triple-flip roll
连续跳跃，接着…
with a double leap, and...
你怎么在这里？！
What are you doing?!
原来是纸做的
That's just paper.
你是在偷看吗？
Were you spying on me?
不是，我只是顺路过来说一声，  我不希望你觉得…
No! I just came by to say  that I don't want you to think...
我不希望你觉得我是某种权威人物
I don't want you to think of me  as some sort of authority figure.
别多想，我没有
Don't worry. I don't.
- 你没有吗？  - 完全没有
- You don't?  - Not at all.
好吧，其他马戏团的动物可能觉得我有点吓人
Well, the other circus animals  might find me a bit intimidating.
不，没有人觉得你吓人
No. Nobody is intimidated at all by you.
哦，不错，好消息
Oh, good stuff. Good. Good news.
事实上，我觉得他们
In fact, I do not think
根本就不把你当回事
they have given you a second thought  since you showed up.
听上去不错
That's good to hear.
如果非要有点什么，  他们会同情你
If anything,  they're starting to feel sorry for you.
好，我明白了，好吗？
OK, I get it. OK?
你还想说什么吗？
Is there more?
我想谢谢你，让我们上了这列火车
I just wanted to thank you  for letting us get on the train back there.
我知道那个说话带口音的猫…
I know the big cat with the accent...
不怎么欢迎我们上来
...wasn't so excited  about us getting on.
听着，狮子
Look, lion guy.
这个马戏团是我们的一切
This circus means everything to us.
如果你做了任何威胁到马戏团的事情
And if you do anything  that threatens this circus,
我会给你好看，明白吗？
you will have to answer to me. Capisce?
明白，好  相信我，我明白
I capisce, cool. Trust me, we're cool.
这还低调？
You call this laying low?
快点，快点！
Faster! Faster!
有马戏团的地方，就有狮子
Where there is circus, there is lion.
在罗马…
And when in Rome...
法兰西万岁！
Vive la France!
停下
Halt!
来吧，我的毛茸茸女王，  我们去万神殿做甜甜圈
Come on, my hairy queen.  We'll do doughnuts in the Pantheon.
你闯大祸了
You're in big trouble.
现在你真的闯大…
Now you're really in big troub...
现在你真的闯了非常非常大的…
Now you're really, really in big tro...
我是新来的！
I'm new!
好，乐队开始演奏！
OK! Strike up the band!
还有乐队？
You have a band?
等着被震撼吧！
Prepare to be blown away!
- 来吧！  - 走起！
- Blow me away!  - Here we go!
瞧这个！
Look at this. Whoa! Hey!
很荣幸能…
It's nice to be...
额…
Yay...
嘿！
Hey!
哇哦，狗狗很逼真吧？
Whoa! How do dogs do that?
上真家伙了！
Get on with it!
蠢货！
Stupido!
这回买票值了
Well, that was worth  the price of admission.
小心！
Watch it, mate!
哪位朋友来自辛辛那提？
Who's from Cincinnati?
斯蒂芬诺，告诉我“震撼”是褒义词，  对不对？
Stefano, you know  "blown away" means good, right?
别担心，高潮要上演了！
Don't worry.  The big finale is coming up!
来个节奏！看这儿！
Give me a downbeat! Look at this!
哦，不，不是吧
Oh, no. No, this is not happening.
成交，我的朋友
You have a deal, mi amigo.
很棒，对不对？
It's good, no?
出去买点吃的再回来吧！
Yes, go out and get food and come back!
(中场休息)
深呼吸，你很开心，事情进展很好
Deep breaths.  You're in a happy place. It's all good.
尽管外面一群民众很生气
There's an angry mob outside,
他们要求退票！
and they're demanding  their money back!
我想我们都知道该怎么做
I think we all know the right thing to do.
快，赶紧！
Come on, come on!
快上，赶紧！
Come on! Hurry up!
跳上火车！
Hop on the train!
快上来，伙计们！
Come on, guys!
妈妈咪呀！
Mamma mia!
赶紧！
Hurry up!
谢谢，亚力斯
Grazie, Alice.
把钱扔给我们就好了！
Just throw us the money!
香塔尔·杜波依队长，起床了
Captain Chantal Dubois. Get up.
我们将会最高戒备，送您回到摩纳哥
I'm going to have to send you back  to Monaco under maximum security.
什么？！
What?!
是枕头！
It's just a pillow!
司令，这是书上最古老的把戏了
That's the oldest trick  in the book, Comandante.
意大利的小毛头都知道这种把戏
Every bambino in ltaly knows that one.
也许吧，但是小毛头知道
Maybe, but do they know  about the old escape hole
不起眼的海报后面，  藏着古老的逃生洞吗？
behind the innocent-looking poster?
或者，真正古老的“躲在天花板上”！
Or the really old "I'm gonna  hide up on the ceiling" trick!
当然
Of course.
还有床底下的秘密隧道！
The secret tunnel under the bed!
把床挪开
Get this thing out of the way.
我们下去！
Let's go!
这个秘密隧道是死胡同！
This secret tunnel is a dead end!
除了弹簧和床垫，什么都没有！
There's nothing but bedsprings  and mattress stuffing down here!
那是关门的声音吗？
Was that the sound  of a cell door closing?
就是它！
Voil?
那是我的惠普打印机的声音吗？
Was that the sound  of my HP printer printing?
(中央公园动物园的明星狮子仍杳无音讯)
真是场灾难！
This is a disaster!
所有的钱都花在了烂马戏团上，  却都没有离纽约近一丁点！
We blow all our money on a bad circus,  and we're not any closer to New York!
怕是越来越远了！
If anything, we're further away!
我们至少应该买一个会表演的马戏团！
We could have at least bought a circus  that knew how to circ!
我都不知道一开始为什么要买下它
I don't even know why we bought  a circus in the first place.
我们的钱都够用来买飞机了！
We had enough dough for a plane!
你开玩笑吧？
Are you kidding me?
你肯定还有钱没花完
You must have some money left over.
我花钱装了假牙，还镀了层金
I used it to buy teeth  and then have them capped in gold.
这样我就能吃苹果了！
Now I can eat apples!
可惜，我发现我不喜欢吃苹果
Sadly, I discovered I don't like apples.
没人会赞助这支马戏团去美国，  完结了！
No promoter is sending this show  to America. It's toe up!
现在说得通了
Now it all makes sense.
怪不得马戏团老板巴不得卖掉它
No wonder the circus master  was so happy to sell.
他当然开心，烂摊子都甩给我们了！
He was happy, all right.  Happy about ripping us off!
亚力克斯去哪儿了？
Where did Alex go?
不知道
I don't know.
快过来，这里！
Come on! This way!
不不不，你过来！
No, no, no. You come this way!
亚力斯，小心头！
Alice, watch your head!
亚力斯！
Alice!
我没事！
I'm fine!
太厉害了！
Fantastic!
这就是美式飞人吗？
Was that trapeze americano?
额，算是吧
Yeah. Sort of.
太不可思议了！
Incredible!
希望是重要的事情
I hope this is important.
这边走，亚力斯！
Come this way, Alice!
额，是“克斯”不是“斯”，  亚力克斯，和纽约尼克斯一样
By the way, it's "icks" not "iss".  Alex. Like New York Knicks.
我知道，纽约尼斯嘛，发音不难的
I know. New York Kniss. Is not hard.
哇哦
Whoa.
这是哪儿？
What is this place?
我知道你们觉得我们是一只烂马戏团
I know you think we are  a stinky, poopy circus,
但我得告诉你些事
but there is something you must know.
我们萨拉戈萨马戏团，
There was a time  when Circus Zaragoza,
一度是一支伟大的马戏团！
we were a great circus!
欧罗巴所有马戏团排名第一！
Numero uno in all the Europa!
而维塔利…他是我们中最闪亮的明星
And Vitaly...  he was the biggest star of us all.
他无所畏惧，敢于冒险，总是有新把戏
He was fearless.  Taking risks. Always new.
他跳起来能飞一样穿过铁环！
He jump through the hoop  like he could fly!
斯蒂芬诺！
Stefano!
拿个小点的环
Make the hoop smaller.
这样呢？
Like this?
再小点
Smaller.
- 这样？  - 行！
- Like this?  - Good!
这个可谓前无古人，  因为物理上根本不可能！
It had never been done before  because it was physically impossible!
而观众…他们超喜欢！
And the people... they loved it!
维塔利万岁！
Viva Vitaly!
再小点！
Smaller!
环，就越变越小！
And the hoop, she got smaller!
就像是豌豆公主
Like the ring
那纤细的手指上的戒指一样大
on a finger of the tiniest lady  with the slimmest of fingers.
太棒了，维塔利！
Bravo, Vitaly!
他从未停止过挑战自己
He would not stop pushing.
终于有一天…
And one fateful day...
…太过了！
...he push too far!
点火！
Light the hoop on fire!
他太过靠近太阳…最终烧伤了自己
He fly too close to the sun...  and he got burned.
是真的烧伤，他身上的橄榄油特别易燃
Literally. The extra virgin olive oil  is extra flammable.
他失去了一切
And he lost everything.
她的妻子，跟一个音乐家跑了
His wife, she run off with a musician.
他的尊严…他的荣耀…
He lost his dignity... his fame...
…他的热情…还有他的毛发
...his passion... and his fur.
新长出来的毛没以前那么软了，  更像是扎人的胡须
And when it grow back, it is less soft.  More like a prickly beard.
对不起，维塔利！
Scusi. Vitaly!
当我没说！
Nothing!
他现在唯一的兴趣就是罗宋汤
His only passion now is the borscht.
哇哦
Whoa.
他曾经是我们的中流砥柱
He was our inspiration.
所以当他热情不再，
So when he lost his passion,
马戏团也每况愈下
well... as Vitaly goes,  so goes the circus.
因而我们需要你们的帮助
This is why we need your help.
什么样的帮助？
What sort of help?
你可以教我们新的马戏，美式马戏！
You can teach us to do new circus.  Americano style!
我们要找回激情，
We find a new passion.
来场全新的演出，直达美！利！坚！
Make a new show.  And we go all the way to US and A!
好吧，这是个白痴的点子
I know. It is stupido idea.
我们是败军之将
We are a lost cause.
不不，这个点子不错，行得通！
No, no, this isn't stupido.  This could work!
- 什么？  - 你刚刚说的那个
- What?  - What you just said.
- 什么？  - 你刚出的主意啊，两秒钟之前那个
- What?  - The idea you said. Two seconds ago.
- 什么？  - 你那个白痴的点子！
- What?  - Your stupido idea!
- 可以吗？  - 斯蒂芬诺，你是天才！
- It could?  - Stefano, you're a genius!
不不不，我只是一般聪明啦
No, no, no, no.  I am only average intelligence.
还有人说我比一般聪明再笨一点
Some say I'm even slightly below.
我们要重新考虑马戏团现有的节目！
We are gonna rethink everything  anybody's ever known about circus!
我称为计划4-7B
I call it Phase 4-7B,
根据计划，为了回家
wherein, in order to get home,
我们要创造些新的东西，
we will come up with something fresh,
一些新奇的，崭新的
something amazing,  something brand-new!
新鲜的，前所未有的，非比寻常的
Fresh, never before seen!  Off the chain!
会震撼到马戏团赞助商的东西！
Something that'll blow  that circus promoter away!
歪了
I missed.
- 砍掉你的头！  - 我咬下他的腿！
- Off with your head!  - I'm gonna chew his leg off!
马戏团代代相传就是那样的！
Circus has been same for generations!
我们创作优秀经典的家庭娱乐，
We make good,  classic family entertainment.
但上几代人，
But last few generations,
“家庭”…不怎么喜欢
families... not so entertained.
的确是这样，一家子都不喜欢
That's right.  Families not so entertained
是因为你们的表演像是走过场
because you're just going  through the motions out there.
没有激情
It's missing passion.
“虎子”都戳到脸上了，  还怎么激情？
How one to have passion  for stool poked in face?
就是！你说的“虎子”是指凳子，对吧？
Exactly! And by stool  you mean chair, right?
你们太拘泥于现状
The fact is, you guys,  you got stuck in a rut.
不再挑战自己，不再勇于冒险
You stopped pushing,  you stopped taking risks.
就让那些日子成为历史吧
But those days are over.
因为现在，我们要彻底改变表演
Because now we're going  to completely change the show.
那就不是马戏团了，不是吗？
Then it wouldn't be a circus, would it?
马戏团无关乎表演
Circus is not about the acts you do.
马戏团关乎于此
Circus is in here.
为什么弗莱迪能得到所有的马戏团？
How come Freddie gets all the circus?
马戏团在于激情所向，不论你去哪里！
Circus is about following your passions,  wherever they take you!
你不能改变马戏团，  它有着悠久的历史！
You cannot change circus.  There is long tradition!
大家曾经都是这么想的，维塔利
That's what everybody thought, Vitaly,
直到那些法裔加拿大人来了
until those French Canadians  came along,
喝着枫糖浆，使用廉价药
drunk off their maple syrup  and cheap pharmaceuticals,
彻底地颠覆了传统
and completely flipped the paradigm.
现在他们在拉斯维加斯表演  52个不同的舞台，每天演50场
Now they play Vegas.  Fifty shows a day in 52 separate venues.
其中有个人还是全裸表演
And one of them  completely in the nude.
对，说的没错，你知道怎么做到的吗？
Yeah, that's right.  And you know how they did it?
脱衣服？
Take off their clothes?
- 不，他们抛弃了所有动物  - 你说什么？
- No. They got rid of the animals.  - What?
- 快说不是这样的！  - 他们白痴吗，不要动物…
- Say it ain't so!  - Che stupida! No animals...
- 怎么能这样？！  - 好了，知道我怎么想吗！
- How could they?!  - Well, you know what I say to that!
我说，他们能把动物赶出马戏团，
I say they can take  the animals out of the circus,
但不能把他们从马戏团名单上划走！
but they cannot take  the animals out of the circus!
我是说，他们不能…
I mean, they cannot...
我想你们懂的！
I think you understand what I'm saying!
- 是！  - 懂！
- Yeah!  - Yes!
不能！
No!
我们已经有激情了，  我们才不需要人类
We don't need humans  because we've got passion.
人有激情的时候，他会说什么？
What does a human say  when he's passionate?
他会说“我是一头野兽！”，  而我们就是野兽
He says, "I'm an animal!"  Well, we are animals!
我们要打造一支全动物的马戏团！
We'll make an all-animal circus!
因为如果我们心随意动，我们将无所不能
Because if we follow our passion,  we can go anywhere.
- 无所不能！  - 所向无敌！
- Anywhere!  - We can do anything!
- 无所不能！  - 只要我们团结起来！
- Anything!  - If we do it together!
- 我们一起！  - 好…太好了，赞成！
- All of us!  - Yeah... Yeah, yeah!
- 我们自己的马戏团！  - 耶！
- Our circus!  - Yeah!
我们加入，我们就这么做！
We're in! We'll have some of that!
大声点，“野兽力量”！
Can I hear you say "fur power"?
野兽力量！
Fur power!
重新开张，齐心协力！
Take our circus back,  and we'll do it together!
我和你，宝贝，我们一起！
You and me, baby! An act together!
我喜欢！
I love it!
我们可以一起跳爵士舞！
We can do  that funk and groove dance thing!
- 跳舞？  - 是啊，就是这样
- Dance?  - This thing right here. Look.
我跟你，我们可以的！
Me and you! We got this!
但我不会跳舞
But I can't dance.
野兽力量！
Fur power!
喊口号真好玩！喊口号真好玩！
Chanting is fun! Chanting is fun!
我不信任这个狮子
I do not trust this lion.
维塔利，我也不怎么相信他
Vitaly, I may not trust him, either,
但干坐着，干站着，  滚来滚去这套，我实在是烦了
but I am tired of sitting  and standing and rolling over.
这是都是优秀的传统
It is great tradition  of sitting, standing, rolling over.
你知道我们的马戏团有麻烦了
You know our circus is in trouble.
这可能是我们最后的机会了，  但我们不能没有你
This could be our last chance.  But we will not do this without you.
马戏团总是团结在一起
Circus always stay together.
好吧，我试试，就钻一次环
OK. I do one hoop.
我也要抱一下！
I want a hug, too!
注意！我找到狮子了，他躲在马戏团里！
Attention! I have found our lion!  He is hiding with the circus!
来，莫瑞斯（其实在叫马蒂），给我吧！
Come on, Maurice, give it to me!
多加点火药，理科！  我真的很想飞起来！
More boomstick, Rico!  I really want to fly!
你真的要把自己射出去？
Are you really going  to shoot yourself out of that thing?
从我还小的时候，我就憧憬
I've always dreamed of doing this,  from time I was a little pup,
成为一枚人肉炮弹！
to be a human cannonball!
不过是，你懂的…海狮炮弹
Except, you know...  a sea lion cannonball.
很危险吧？
Is it dangerous?
危险？当然危险！
Is it dangerous?  Yes, of course it's dangerous!
- 这样你还要做？  - 当然
- Now, are you sure about this?  - I'm sure.
要是“震撼”是你的座右铭，你来对地方了
'Cause if blowing up is your thing,  then you in the right place.
是，没错！
Si. That's means yes!
准备发射？
Ready for launch?
准备好了！
Ready for launch!
开火！
Fire in the hole!
等等！
Wait!
不要！
Mamma mia!
救命！
Help me!
里科！准备好炮弹！同样的动力！
Rico! Get the cannon ready!  Same charge!
开火！
Fire in the hole!
太好了！
All right!
耶！
Yeah!
马蒂！太好了，你在这儿
Marty! I'm so glad you're here.
我在飞！我真的在弗诶飞！
I was flying! I was effin'-L-Y-in'!
真为你开心，但是…
I'm proud of you, but...
…我就要支撑不住了！
...I don't think  I can hold on much longer!
好，没问题，不好意思我太高兴了
Oh, yeah, right.  Sorry about my enthusiasm.
抓住绳子，套身上
Here, wrap this around you.
没事没事，我抓着呢！
All right, I got you! I got you!
忘掉自己是蹄类吧！我快成为鸟类了！
Forget about being part of the herd!  I'm gonna be part of the flock!
我会飞了耶！
I'm going to fly, baby!
是啊！成了！
Oh, yes! What a triumph!
- 交出马戏团来，弗莱迪！  - 我扯掉你肠子当吊带！
- Hand over that circus, Freddie!  - I'll have your guts for garters!
嘿嘿，放下武器
Hey, hey, put your weapons down.
冷静一下，伙计们，  装可爱显然不是你们的强项
Guys, chill out. Cute and cuddly's  obviously not your thing.
他说到点子上了
He's got us pegged.
我有个更好的主意，给他们看看，里科
I got a better idea. Show 'em, Rico.
太棒了！
That was great!
- 滑板！  - 火箭鞋！
- Flippin' 'eck!  - Rocket shoes!
我想穿穿看！
I want to try that!
乔纳斯，乔纳斯！
Jonesy! Jonesy!
嘿，嗨
Hey. Hi.
激将法用得真不错
I admire how you  have inspired these animals.
谢谢
Thanks.
你谈论激情的时候，像在读诗一样
And what you said about passion,  it was like poetry.
我喜欢激情和诗歌，它们其实是一回事
I love passion and poetry.  They go together, really.
虽然不押韵
I know they don't rhyme.
空中飞人是我的热情所在！
Trapeze is my passion!
好极了，期待看到你表演
Terrific. I look forward  to seeing you up there.
你可以教我啊！
You can teach me!
- 什么？  - 教我
- What?  - Teach me.
额，我一直是单独表演
Well, I've always  been kind of a solo act.
所以规则不一样啦
So that kind of rules that out.
我在想，你是不是真的会空中飞人
I wonder if you actually do trapeze.
- 哦，我真的会  - 让我瞧瞧！
- Oh, I actually do do trapeze.  - Show me!
“让我瞧瞧”？我们还是五岁小孩么？
"Show me"? What are we, five?
对啊，我就是五岁
I am five, yes.
跳舞
Dancing.
你只要动动脚就好，哪儿都不要去
All you're doing is moving  and not getting anywhere.
音乐让我太过忘我
I mean, the music  totally throws off my timing.
来点刺激的？
You want excitement?
看看谁在钢丝上，哼？
Check it out. Who's on a tightrope, huh?
谁在…
Who's on a...
我在钢丝绳上！我在钢丝绳上！
I'm on a tightrope!  I'm on a tightrope!
梅尔曼，我的天啊！
Melman! Oh, my gosh!
- 救我！  - 亲爱的，坚持住，坚持住
- Help me!  - Baby, hold on. Hold on.
我现在就来！
I'm coming right now!
梅尔曼？！
Melman?!
冷静，梅尔曼
Calm down, Melman.
我要掉下去摔断脖子了！
I'm going to fall  and break all of my neck!
看着我，看着我
Just look at me. Look at me.
- 全神贯注看着我  - 好
- All eyes on me.  - OK.
- 来这边  - 我做不到
- Come to me.  - I can't.
就像跳舞一样，梅尔曼，进两步，退一步
It's just like dancing, Melman.  Two steps forward, one step back.
我不会跳舞，知道吗？我说过了
I can't dance, OK? There, I said it.
也许是因为你没试过呢
Maybe because you've never tried.
我试过了
No, I have tried.
因为你跳得太好，我私下偷偷练习来着
I practiced in private  because you dance so well.
你练过了？为了我？
You practiced? For me?
是，但是没用
Yes, but it's no use.
我不知道我的手要怎么放
I never know  what to do with my arms.
抓着我
Hold it.
那部分很简单的，梅尔曼
That part is so easy, Melman. OK?
你只要把手放在舞伴身上就好了
'Cause all you have to do  is put them around your partner.
看见吗，进两步？
See? Two steps forward.
退一步
One step back.
- 我在跳舞，我在跳舞！  - 进两步…
- I'm dancing. I'm dancing!  - Two steps forward...
- 我们在钢丝上跳舞！  - 你跳得很好呢
- We're dancing on a tightrope!  - You're great.
我能跳舞了！
I'm dancing!
好了
OK.
好
All right.
我们什么时候用上喷气背包和眼镜水蛇？
So when do we get  the jet packs and aquatic cobras?
这节是初级课，那些太高级了
This is a beginners' class,  and that's a pretty advanced maneuver.
好，怎么开始？
OK, how do we begin?
说起来有点复杂，除非你搞清楚
It's a bit complicated  unless you understand
这整个装置和脚…角度还有重力
the whole pitch and yaw...  arc and gravity.
这些东西，肯定会让你无聊的，肯定会
All that stuff,  which I won't bore you with. OK.
- 要我推一下吗？  - 不用
- Do you need a push?  - No.
看着学就行了！
Just watch and learn!
这样吗？
Like that?
当然啦，这是一种方式
That's one way of doing it, sure.
你用了网！
You use a net!
是！美式飞人，我们用网
Yes! Trapeze americano. We use the net.
美式飞人！
Trapeze americano!
快看他！
Look at him go!
哇！
Wow!
太棒了，鼓掌！
E bravo! Bravissima!
维塔利，你想不想多钻一次环？
Hey, Vitaly,  maybe you even do two hoops, no?
疯女人，拉响警报
Senorita, Bell-bottoms.
我们遇上大问题了
Tenemos una problema grande.
大，大问题？
Que? Que? Grande problema?
哦不，她要找到我们了！
Oh, no! She's onto us!
不要把那个疯子引过来
Don't make it any easier on the psycho.
- 我们怎么办？  - 我们最好赶紧离开，赶紧准备
- What are we gonna do?  - We'd better vamoose... pronto.
但我们还没结束呢，还在排练当中
But we're not ready.  We're in the middle of rehearsals.
那你就哼哼小曲儿
Then why don't you lilt over,
摘摘小花儿，跟纽约吻别吧？
grab your peduncle,  and kiss New York good-bye?
我们真的准备好了吗？
Are you sure we are ready?
当然啦，早就准备好了！  准备得太好了！来吧，我们走！
Of course we're ready! Born ready!  Ready steady! Come on, let's go!
出发！我们走！
Let's go, go, go, go, go!
好吧，你们听到那只猫的话了，  走吧，来！启程！
All right, you heard the cat.  Move it! Come on! All aboard!
带好行李，上好厕所
Grab your luggage  and drain your bladders.
这将是漫长的旅程！
It's going to be a long ride!
好啦，我们来震撼赞助商吧！
All right, everybody,  let's blow that promoter away!
伦敦，我们来了！
London, here we come!
阳光明媚的伦敦！我们来了！
Sunshiny London, yes!
维塔利，维塔利，维塔利！
Vitaly! Vitaly! Vitaly!
(伦敦)
快点，快点，他在哪儿？
Come on, come on, come on.  Where is he?
找到了！
Bingo!
如果此人不是精力充沛的赞助商，  我不知道还能是谁了
If that's not a red-blooded  American promoter, I don't know what is.
我们要踏踏实实做好演出，  二等兵！告诉他们飞鹰已着陆
We need to get this show on the road.  Private! Tell them the eagle has landed.
飞鹰已着陆！
The eagle has landed!
知道了，盯好杜波依
Roger that.  And keep an eye out for Dubois.
收到，老大！
Aye, aye, guvnor!
赞助商在场！
The promoter is in the house!
纽约近在咫尺！
New York is closer than ever!
别高兴太早
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
我们首先要表演好马戏，上场了
First, we got a circus to do.  We're on, folks!
- 我们在狗狗之前还是之后上场？  - 是的
- Do we go on before or after the dogs?  - Yes.
- 什么？  - 一起，你们一起上场
- What?  - Overlap, your acts overlap.
- 维塔利在哪儿？他开场  - 不知道
- Where's Vitaly? He opens.  - I don't know.
斯蒂芬诺！嘿，斯蒂芬诺！  你看到维塔利了吗？
Stefano! Hey, Stefano!  Have you seen Vitaly?
嘿
Hey.
斯蒂芬诺，伤心什么呢？
Stefano, why the sad little face?
维塔利…他不会上场了！
Vitaly... he will not go on!
什么？
What?
我尽力了
I tried everything I could.
擦干眼泪，冷静下来
Wipe away the tears. Calm down.
他在哪儿？我可以说服他
Where is he?  I'm sure I can reason with him.
维塔利，你在干嘛？
Vitaly, what are you doing?
你打歪了
You missed.
你要走？你就这么放弃大家了？
You're leaving? You're just gonna  walk out on everybody?
没有我，你们的表演一样很精彩
They have good show without me.
看着，我左脚很健康，  但是没有右脚，我就走不了
Look, I got a good left foot,  but without my right foot, I can't walk.
装个假肢你就能走了
You get fake foot, then you walk.
我才不装假肢，好吗？
I don't want fake foot! OK?
“马戏团团结在一起”这句是空话么，  “一直演下去”呢？
What happened to "circus stick  together"? "The show must go on".
都是老掉牙了
Cliches.
拜托，我不要这个维塔利！  我要另一个维塔利！
Come on, man.  Stop being this guy! Be the other guy!
什么另一个？
What other guy?
那个是马戏团的中流砥柱的你！  那个穿过铁环的你！
The guy who was all circus!  The guy who jumped through hoops!
回归那个你！那个受到大家的景仰的你！
Give me that!  The guy everybody looked up to.
那个维塔利在哪里？
Come on. Where's that Vitaly?
他死了
That Vitaly is no more.
听着，你可以自暴自弃，
Listen, man.  You may have given up on yourself,
但你的朋友从来没放弃过你
but your friends  haven't given up on you.
你想在余生，转过身去背对他们，
Are you just going  to turn your back on them,
一个人默默喝一辈子罗宋汤？
and sit and eat borscht  the rest of your life?
还是，你现在走出去，  上台穿过那个小小的铁环？
Or are you gonna get out there  and jump through that tiny little hoop?
不可能的
It is impossible.
因为不可能，维塔利，所以人们才喜欢
It was always impossible, Vitaly.  That's why the people loved it.
这也是我也喜欢的原因
That is why I loved it.
因为我做到了不可能的事情！
Because I did the impossible!
我曾经是个勇敢的老虎
I was once a brave tiger.
在火焰中倒下…
And if I go down in flames...
…又算得了什么！
...so be it!
我也许可以帮你出个主意
You know, I think  I might have an idea for you.
(护发素)
点火吧！
Light the hoop on fire!
妈妈咪呀，圣母保佑，圣母保佑…
Mamma mia, Santa Maria, Santa Maria...
妈妈咪呀，圣母保佑，圣子保佑…
Mamma Maria, mia Santa,  Santa Mia Farrow...
加油，你可以的
Come on, you got it.
太好了！
Yes!
好了，还愣着干嘛？  我们有演出呢
All right, what are you waiting for?  We got a show to put on.
上场，出发！
Let's go. Go, go, go, go, go!
看！
Look!
我们要去美国啦！
We're going to America!
今天就去！
Today!
这就是我所说的当梦想照进现实！
That's what I call crack-a-lackin'  to the mack-a-lackin'!
- 我们做到了，亚力斯！  - 是啊！
- We did it, Alice!  - Yeah!
也许我还是有一般聪明的！
Maybe I am  average intelligence after all!
有可能还略高于一般聪明
Perhaps even slightly above.
不，我不觉得
No, I don't think so.
护发素，好想法啊，兄弟！
Hair conditioner. Great idea, my friend!
摸摸看，快，小猫一样软，是不是？
Feel. Go ahead. Soft like kitten, no?
看看
Look at that.
又滑又不易燃
Slippery but not flammable.
你闻上去有桃子和青草的味道！
You smell like peaches and herb!
吉亚和亚力克斯，空中飞猫！
Gia and Alex, the trapezing cats!
我们棒极了
We did pretty good.
你空翻，我来接
You will flip, and I will catch.
有时候我空翻，你来接
And sometimes I will flip,  and you will catch.
然后我们俩一起空翻，  我们能世界巡演了！
And then we will both flip,  and we'll travel the whole world!
旋转跳跃，我闭着眼…
Flipping and catching,  and I will flip you...
你知道，其实…
You know, the thing is...
我不会一直呆这儿
I may not always be around.
你要去那儿？
Where are you going?
我…我…我…
Well, I'm... I'm... I'm...
很好嘛，很好！
Bravo, bravo!
真是温暖人心的表演，  马戏团老板先生
What a heartwarming performance,  Monsieur Circus Master.
看得我热泪盈眶
It brought tears to my eyes.
不，骗你的
No, not really.
先生，我们都知道，狮子不属于你
Monsieur, we both know  the lion does not belong to you.
是那个怪女人！
It's that horrid woman!
他是警察局的逃犯
He is a fugitive from justice.
你可以把狮子交给我了
You will turn the lion over to me
这样我可以送他去该去的地方
so that I may put him  where he belongs.
挂在我墙上
On my wall.
- 什么？  - 入！
- What?  - lncoming!
出！
Outgoing!
等等！
Wait!
击掌！
Up high!
太低，太慢
Down low. Too slow.
- 干得好，二等兵  - 真的吗？
- Well done, Private.  - Did I do good?
骗你的
Nah, not really.
好险啊！
Man, that was close!
亚力克斯？
Alex?
你是动物园来的？
You are from a zoo?
是，不过等等，不只是这样
Yes. Yes. But wait, there's more.
- 不只？  - 或是不全是，不全是那样
- More?  - Or less. There's less.
你没待过马戏团？
You were never circus?
我们不得不说自己是从马戏团来的
We had to say we were circus.
不然你们都不让我们上车！
Or you'd never have let us on the train!
毕竟我们一起奋斗过…
After all we have  been through together...
…你想回去住动物园吗？
...you want to go live in a zoo?
- 吉亚，我…  - 你利用了我们
- Gia, l...  - You used us.
不不不，我是说，是的，但是…
No, no, no. I mean, yes, but...
美式飞人，这也是编出来的吗？
Trapeze americano,  you make that up, too?
我教你的时候其实没有这个把戏
It didn't exactly exist  when I taught it to you.
喷气背包和眼镜水蛇！  我早该知道的
Jet packs and aquatic cobras!  I should have known.
给孩子的气球也不是真的？
Balloons to the children of the world  was not real, either?
嗯，不是真的，但是看看我们做了什么
Yeah, that's not real.  But look at what we did.
我被一门大炮射出去！  差点死掉！
I was shot out of a cannon!  I could have died!
我以为这是你毕生梦想呢
But I thought it was  your lifelong dream.
这么说，亚力斯都不是你的真名
For all I know,  your name is not even Alice.
不是，斯蒂芬诺，确实不是这么叫的
No, Stefano, but it never really was.
我现在没有安全感了！
I don't feel safe!
吉亚，我…
Gia, l...
我们信任过你
We trusted you.
我的眼泪是真的！
My tears are real!
你不是真的！
You are not!
真不敢相信，  你欺骗了我们一马戏团的人
I can't believe you lied  to all us circus folk.
我？留在马戏团？
Me? Stay with the circus?
我是帝王之命！我要统治纽约！  我们应该好好谈谈
I am a king! I want to rule New York!  We should talk.
哇哦！
Whoa!
住手！说不行就不行，用你的话说…
Stop it! No means no!  Or in your language...
这解决不了问题
Not everything  is solved that way, you know.
索尼娅，你在听我说吗？
Sonya? Are you listening to me?
现在我被冷暴力了，是吗？
Now I'm getting  the silent treatment, am l?
过来，立刻马上！
Come over here, right now!
不要这样！
Don't shut me out, baby!
你怎么了啊！说话啊！
What is wrong with you? Speak!
好吧…如果你的感情只是这样，我明白了
OK... if these are your feelings,  I understand now.
我走就是了！
And I'm going!
看来我只是你人生中不起眼的一小部份！
It's obvious I'm just an emotional  whoopee cushion for you to sit on!
你以后想找我，
When you look for where I am,
再也找不到了！
I won't be there!
(纽约城)
来吧，各位，我们还有表演要做
Come, everybody.  We have show to do.
但是没有马蒂，我要怎么做？
But how do I go on without Marty?
- 斯蒂芬诺  - 我不知道怎么做了
- Stefano.  - I don't know what to do.
你还是可以表演单人炮
You can still do cannon solo.
但是…我想跟马蒂一起做单人表演！
But... I want to do solo act with Marty!
我怎么办呢？
And what do I do?
重新回到坐下，起立，翻滚嘛？
Go back to sitting  and standing and rolling over?
不
No.
我们可以做不可能的事情！
We can do impossible!
而且，我们不要重归平淡
And we never go back  to way we used to be.
平淡不是以前的样子
The way it used to be  isn't the way it was.
没有他们什么都变了，  干什么不都一样么
And it won't be the same without them,  whatever way it is.
(中央公园动物园)
好了，我们到了
Well... we're here.
到家了
Home.
我记得我的石头没这么小的
My rock looks smaller  than I remember it.
看那张壁画
Look at the mural.
一点都不像，是吧？
Doesn't actually capture  the real thing, does it?
诶
Wow.
我都忘了我们之间还有一堵墙了，  梅尔曼
I forgot about that wall  in between us, Melman.
一直都有吗？
Was that always there?
伙计们，对不起，我从一开始就不该离开动物园的
Guys, I'm sorry  I ever left the zoo in the first place.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我说，如果我乖乖待着不动，
I mean, if I had just stayed put,
我们现在就不会难过了
we wouldn't have  anything to be sad about right now.
离开动物园是做过的最棒的事情
Leaving the zoo was the best thing  that ever happened to us.
真的吗？
Really?
是啊，在外面广阔的世界里，  我们才真正地活着
Yeah. Out there, in the world,  we were really living.
- 是啊！  - 很有趣！
- Yeah!  - It was exciting!
- 很浪漫  - 很危险
- It was romantic.  - It was dangerous.
从来没有这么活着过！
I never felt so alive!
我们进马戏团的时候，我们就已经回家了
When we were with the circus,  we were already home.
真希望我早点能认识到这点
I only wish we'd realized that sooner.
我真的很想那些家伙
I'm really going to miss those guys.
你们觉得，我们回去怎么样？
What do you say we go back?
真的吗？
Really?
- 我也要回去！  - 我也要！
- I'm with you!  - I'm in!
但我们要怎么跟他们说呢？
But what do we tell them?
我们跟他们认错就好了
We make it right by telling them  how wrong we were.
值得一试
It's worth a shot.
在火焰中倒下，又算得了什么！
And if we go down in flames, so be it!
- 好，就这么干！  - 我赞成！
- Yes, let's do this!  - I like it!
好，我们回去！
Yeah, yeah!
我的脖子变长了吗？
Is my neck getting longer?
摸摸看我的毛，好软啊
Feel my fur. It's so soft.
好软
It is soft.
我就像黑白片里的甘蔗
I'm like a candy cane  in a black and white movie.
哦不
Oh, no.
杜波依
Dubois.
索尼娅，我想你了！宝贝！  我想你了，你这臭臭的熊！
Sonya, I miss you, baby!  I miss my stinky bear!
宝贝…你湿湿的吻！
Babe... your fishy kisses!
惊喜吧！
Surprise!
他塞不进行李箱
He will never fit in the carry-on.
但他的头可以！
But his head will!
- 嘿！  - 什么人？
- Hey!  - Qu'est-ce Que c'est?
看，看看她做了什么！
Look! Look what she's done!
你把亚力克斯带回来了！
You brought back Alex the lion!
- 奇迹啊  - 谢谢，谢谢！
- It's a miracle!  - Thank you! Thank you!
索尼娅，你在哪儿？
Sonya, where are you?
索尼娅！
Sonya!
对不起
Excuse me.
索尼娅宝贝！
Sonya, baby!
我不要当王了！
I don't want to be king anymore!
我过去太在乎我是谁…
I was so hung up on who I was...
…你是谁…和你的味道…
...who you was...  what you smelled like...
…重要的是我们俩一起臭味相投
...when all that really matters  is what we smell like together.
我就知道！
I know!
宝贝，原谅我
Baby, forgive me.
嗨，好吗？
Oh, hello?
这…这是杜波依！
Gasp! It's Dubois!
我的天哪！
Baba booey!
这哪儿来的？
Where did you get this?
动物园来的
I got it from the zoo.
那群人中了埋伏了！
The hippies got ambushed!
什么？我们必须要帮他们！
What? We have to help them!
但他们骗了我们！
But they lied to us!
是啊，我们为什么还要伸出援手？
Yeah. Why should we lift a paw?
他们是我们的朋友！
They are our friends!
他们都不是马戏团的！
They're not even circus!
布尔什维克该站在一起！
That's Bolshevik!
我从没想过在美国大地上说出这样的话，  但俄国佬说得对！
I never thought I'd say this  on American soil, but the Russki's right!
亚力克斯，亚力克斯，亚力克斯，亚力克斯！
Alex! Alex! Alex! Alex!
哦不
Oh, no.
亚力克斯？
Alex?
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
格洛丽亚！你还好吗？
Gloria! Are you OK?
- 发生了什么？  - 亚力克斯！
- What is happening?  - Alex!
- 不不！不不！  - 亚力克狮！
- No, no! No, no!  - Alex the lion!
不！
No!
谢谢，谢谢大家来参加这项特殊的庆典
Thank you. Thank you all for coming  to this special celebration.
现在，创造奇迹的人
And now, the woman  who made this all possible,
她带了亚力克狮和其他两个…
who brought Alex the lion  and a couple of...
…三个？
...three?
其他三个动物回到了纽约
Three other animals back to New York.
她是法国人
And she's French.
让我们欢迎香塔尔·杜波依！
Please welcome Chantal Dubois!
亚力克斯？
Alex?
这不是钱的问题
It was never about the money.
而是…
It was about...
…狮子
...the lion.
- 吉亚？  - 马戏团团结在一起
- Gia?  - Circus stick together.
嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒，马戏团  嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒，爆炸头
Da-da da-da-da-da-da-da, circus  Da-da da-da-da-da-da-da, Afro
马戏团 爆炸头，马戏团 爆炸头  花衬衫，花衬衫！
Circus Afro, Circus Afro  Polka dot, polka dot!
看！会飞的马戏团！
Look! A flying circus!
不！
No!
营救马戏团小组…汇合！
Operation Afro-Circus Rescue... engage!
遵命，老大！
Aye, aye, Skipper!
发射海豹炮弹
Unleash the seal.
- 我是海狮！  - 随便啦
- I am a sea lion!  - Whatever.
大象坠落，冲啊冲啊！
Two tons of fun. Dive, dive, dive!
我们开始吧
Let's rock.
我和你，亲爱的！
You and me, baby!
哇哦！
Wow!
收个小腹！
Suck in that gut!
真不可思议！
I am impressed!
任务完成，现在我们离开这里吧！
Mission accomplished.  Now let's get out of here!
- 等等，等我！  - 斯蒂芬诺！
- Wait! Wait for me!  - Stefano!
不要丢下我！
Don't leave without me!
不！
Oh, no!
快跑，斯蒂芬诺！
Go, Stefano!
爬上来！
Climb!
快啊！
Come on, my friend!
斯蒂芬诺！
Stefano!
救我！
Help me!
我会收着你的脑袋的！
I will have your head!
不要！救我！
Oh, no! Help me!
亚力克斯！
Alex!
马蒂！把我射出去
Marty! Shoot me a line.
好的，哥们，别往我失望啊！
You got it. Afro, don't fail me now!
你要怎么做？
What are you doing?
我们来美式空中飞人
We are doing trapeze americano.
来吧！
Let's do it!
- 弗兰基！乔纳斯！准备好了！  - 随时待命，长官！
- Frankie, Jonesy! Be ready!  - You got it, boss!
出发！
Go, go, go!
吉亚，带斯蒂芬诺走！
Gia! Take Stefano!
亚力克斯！
Alex!
眼镜水蛇！
Aquatic cobras!
如果我掉下去，你的头要陪葬！
If I am going down,  your head is coming with me!
休想！
I don't think so!
轮到我们了！
Oi, let's go!
你自己掉下去吧，恕不奉陪
You're going down,  but not with my head.
喷气背包！他腾空了！
Jet pack! He pull up!
你滥捕动物的日子到头了，杜波依！
Your days of chasing animals  are over, Dubois!
因为你惹到百兽之王了！
Because you've just messed  with the king!
动物们希望你待在这儿！  现在，坐下！
This is where animals like you belong!  Now sit!
躺下
Lie down.
我好调皮呀
Naughty me.
滚几圈
Roll over.
不错嘛，杜波依
Good, Dubois.
呆着吧！
Now stay!
我们成功了！
We did it!
给全世界孩子们的气球！
Balloons to the children of the world!
美式空中飞人！
Trapeze americano!
- 是真的  - 是真的！
- It is real.  - It's real!
你做到了！
That's how you do it!
你们想要跟马戏团一起走吗？
So you want to run away  with the circus?
- 冒险的生活？  - 浪漫的生活？
- Live a life of adventure?  - Full of romance?
- 刺激的生活！  - 真正的生活！
- And danger!  - Really living!
你们说呢？
What do you say?
∮ 啦-嗒 嗒-嗒-嗒-嗒-嗒-嗒，马戏团！ ∮
∮ Ra-da-da da-da-da-da-da-da, circus! ∮
∮ 嗒-嗒 嗒-嗒-嗒-嗒-嗒-嗒，爆炸头！ ∮
∮ Da-da da-da-da-da-da-da, Afro! ∮
∮ 马戏团 爆炸头，马戏团 爆炸头！  花衬衫，花衬衫，花衬衫，爆炸头！ ∮
∮ Circus Afro, Circus Afro!  Polka dot, polka dot, polka dot, Afro! ∮
∮ 我喜欢扭来扭去，扭来扭去  我喜欢扭来扭去，扭来扭去 ∮
∮ I like to move it, move it  I like to move it, move it ∮
∮ 我喜欢扭来扭去，扭来扭去，  你喜欢… ∮
∮ I like to move it, move it  You like to... ∮
∮ 扭来扭去！ ∮
∮ Move it! ∮
老大，话说你是怎么处理那个疯女人的？
Skipper, what did you end up doing  with the crazy lady, anyway?
(运送至：马达加斯加)